# **Zubair Ahmed Khan**



Cell #: +92.314-516.104.9 E-mail: <u>zubair530@gmail.com</u> <u>Skype: zubair530</u>

## **Summary**

An experienced professional, having more than 10 year experience in working on Microsoft Technologies (especially ASP.NET / SQL Server). Have hands on experience in .NET technologies (.NET 1.1 and 2.0, 3.5, 4.0, and 4.5). Have in depth knowledge of C#, VB.NET, SQL Server (2000, 2005, 2008 and 2012), VB and ASP. Experienced in two tier, three tier and N-tier application development (Web and Desktop applications).

#### Specialties:

- Database Systems:
  - SQL Azure, Microsoft SQL Server 2000, 2005, 2008, 2012 and 2014, MySQL, SSIS, DTS
- Development Technologies:
  - > ASP, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Web Services, Desktop Applications
- Programming Languages:
  - Microsoft C#.NET, VB.NET, C++
- Frameworks:
  - NET (1.1, 2.0, 3.5, 4.0, 4.5)
- Markup Languages:
  - > HTML, HTML5, XML, JSON, CSS
- Scripting Languages:
  - AngularJS, Ajax Control Toolkit, JavaScript, jQuery, VBScript, NodeJS
- Development Tools:
  - Microsoft Visual Studio.NET 2010, 2012, 2013, Eclipse
- Microsoft Azure:
  - SQL Azure, Azure Websites/Applications, Mobile Services, Cloud Services
- Unit Testing:
  - Microsoft Fakes, Pex & Moles, MOQ
- Other Tools:
  - Microsoft Team Foundation Server, Tortoise SVN, Bootstrap, SignalR, Microsoft Visio, Fiddler

### **Skills and Competencies:**

- Problem solving skills
- Willingness to learn and apply new technologies quickly
- Good time management skills
- Highly confident, motivated and competent individual with excellent analytical skills.
- Ability to work under pressure and meet deadlines
- Ability to set objectives, supervise, manage time, establish goals.
- Ability to work within a team as well as independently
- Ability of quickly mastering new software and apply its full range of capabilities.
- Fluent in Urdu, Pashto and English.

# **Experience**

> Target Dashboard, Pakistan www.TargetDashbaord.com

**Designation**: Software Engineer (July 2016 – Present)

**Responsibilities**: Addition of new modules and maintenance of their existing CRM and Main Target Dashboard Product.

Vertical Systems Inc. (Now Vasona Systems Inc.), Islamabad <a href="https://www.versys.com">www.versys.com</a> 3<sup>rd</sup> Floor Plaza 2000, I-8 Markaz, Islamabad Pakistan

**Designation**: Senior Software Engineer (August 2014 – June 2016) (**2 years**) **Responsibilities**: Ranged from analyzing, designing, developing and providing support for ASP.Net applications, working on both front-end and server-side. Developed VSi's Inspection Reporting Portal application, used by VSi's customers, to keep track of their room and property inspections. Worked on the server side backend of RoomReady, vInspect and vProp application used by high end hotel chain across the US as well as Casinos in Las Vegas and a 1300 hotel Property Management group out of Florida.

CrossOver / gTeam FZ LLC/Aurea Energy Services: <a href="www.crossOver.com">www.crossOver.com</a> / www.gTeamers.com / www.Aurea.com : (1 year, 3 months)

**Designation**: C# Engineer (November 2014 – January 2016)

**Responsibilities**: Member of the DevOps/Maintenance team, worked on different sections of the Aurea Energy Solutions Product. A versatile product that provide different services to the clients, which has been built utilizing almost all of the .NET technologies, from a console application to web and windows services.

- Worked on Generation of Unit Tests using MOQ, Pex & Moles and Microsoft Unit Tests Technologies.
- Worked on resolving different user tickets related to addition of new features or bug fixing.
- Ovex Technologies, Islamabad <u>www.ovextech.com</u> Ground Floor, Evacuee Trust Complex, F-5/1, Sir Agha Khan Road, Islamabad (2 months)

**Designation**: Senior ASP.NET Developer (May2014 - July2014)

**Responsibilities**: Ovex provides services as Back office to Enpointe Technologies (www.enpointe.com) Gardena, California USA.

Worked on the new version of their in-house project (<a href="www.accesspointe.com">www.accesspointe.com</a>) built using latest technologies (Using MVC 5, .NET version 4.0 and SQL Server 2014, Agile Software Development Process and Onion Architecture).

Datum Square IT Services, Ground Floor, STP3, I 9/3, Islamabad. (3 Years, 5 Months)

**Designation**: Senior Software Engineer (January 2011 to December 2011)
Associate Team Lead (January 2012 to May 2014)

**Responsibilities**: Datum Square is the Pakistan office for the US based company AllShore (<u>www.allshore.us</u>), AllShore provides development services to different US based companies.

Working on in-house projects (e.g. <a href="www.DatumSquare.com">www.DatumSquare.com</a> ) as well as working for offshore client SurferNetwork (<a href="www.SurferNetwork.com">www.SurferNetwork.com</a> ). Working different SurferNetwork applications, in-house (e.g. <a href="mailto:ccp3.surfernetwork.com">ccp3.surfernetwork.com</a> , <a href="mailto:minijoe3.surfernetwork.com">minijoe3.surfernetwork.com</a> ) as well as Surfers' client applications (300+Clients).

White Wings Technologies, House#233B, Street#100, 18/4, Islamabad (2 years)

**Designation**: Software Developer (January 2009 - December 2010) **Responsibilities**: Worked as Employee of White Wings Consulting (www.wwcny.com)

Ovex Technologies, Islamabad <u>www.ovextech.com</u> Ground Floor, Evacuee Trust Complex, F-5/1, Sir Agha Khan Road, Islamabad (3 years, 3 months)

**Designation**: Software Developer (September, 2005 to September, 2008) Senior Software Developer (October, 2008 to December, 2008)

Ovex provides services as Back office to:

- 1. PremiereBPO (www.premierebpo.com) Clarksville Tennessee USA.
- 2. Enpointe Technologies (www.enpointe.com) Gardena, California USA.
- > Fatima Jinnah Women University, Rawalpindi.
  - 1. Taught a course titled ".NET Framework & C# programming" in Fatima Jinnah Women University Rawalpindi, as a visiting faculty member.
  - 2. Supervised projects of students of Fatima Jinnah Women University Rawalpindi, as external supervisor.

# **Education**

- ➤ **MS (Computer Engineering)** from Center for Advanced Studies in Engineering (CASE) (http://www.case.edu.pk). Having CGPA 3.05/4.00
- > MCS from University of Arid Agriculture Rawalpindi. Having CGPA 3.87/4.00.
- > **BSc.** (Computer Science, Physics, Mathematics) From Peshawar University. Securing 60% marks.
- ➤ **FSc**. (Pre-Medical / Additional Mathematics) From Nisar Shaheed Degree College Risalpur Cantt. Pre-Med 68.18%, Pre-Eng 69.82% marks.

# **Achievements**

- Professional
  - ✓ Became the first person in DatumSquare to achieve CEOM Award Twice in November 2013.
  - ✓ Got the most Consistent Employee of the Month (CEOM) Award in DatumSquare
    IT Services in April 2012
  - ✓ Won the Employee Excellence award a record 21 Times in DatumSquare IT Services.
  - ✓ Got Employ of the Month award in June 2006 in Ovex Technologies.
- Academic
  - ✓ First Division Throughout academic career.
  - ✓ Got Vice Chancellor talent scholarship in 2nd Semester of MCS.
  - ✓ Got Merit Scholarship in the 3rd Semester of MCS.

# Some Projects

➤ **VSi Reporting Website**: <a href="http://www.ver-sys.com">http://www.ver-sys.com</a> : Vasona Systems Inc. (formerly Vertical Systems Inc.) has a number of hotels as their clients, this application provides interface for reporting, user management (inspectors, evaluators, users) and management of different services.

### Responsibilities:

- ✓ Management, Creation and Designing of new modules
- √ Maintenance of existing modules
- ✓ Upgrading the website to Microsoft Azure Cloud Storage

# Tools / Technologies:

- ✓ ASP.NET
- √ SQL Azure
- √ Azure Mobile Services
- √ MySQL
- ➤ **VSi Azure Cloud Services**: Different Azure Services which provided backend for real-time synchronization of inspections. The inspections are synchronized as soon as inspection is performed on a mobile device (Android, iOS).

### Tools / Technologies:

- ✓ C#
- √ Azure Mobile Services / Web Jobs
- √ SOAP, REST, WCF Based services
- ➤ Player Applications: SurferNetwork has more than 300 Radio Stations as clients. SurferNetwork provides streaming services and online radio systems for all these stations. Some stations are: <a href="http://katfm.com/">http://katfm.com/</a>, <a href="http://katfm.com/">http://katfm.com/</a>, <a href="http://www.wbmw.com/">http://wbta1490.com/Default.aspx</a>, <a href="http://www.wbmw.com/">http://www.wbmw.com/</a>
  - √ The players are built in SilverLight, .NET uses SQLServer as backend
  - ✓ My role was building of the players and their maintenance.
- ➤ Customer Control Panel (CCP): <u>ccp3.surfernetwork.com</u>: This project provides a Control Panel to the stations for customizing different features of their players.
  - √ The site is built in .NET Technologies and uses SQLServer as DB.
  - √ My role is the building of the site and its maintenance.
- ➤ **MES System** (Money Exchange System): A product that has been customized for 40+ Money transferring Organizations located in different countries of the world (e.g. USA, UK, Brazil, Italy, China, Pakistan etc.)

### MES System in a Glance

- √ A Money Transfer Product that is used for transferring of Money between individuals present in different countries.
- √ The Sender users generate transactions from the web interface and then
  the MES system decides automatically how to transfer the transaction
  to the destination Agencies, depending upon how their system is
  configured for the reception of the transactions. E.g. via Ftp Service,
  Web Service or Manual download.

# **Tools & Technologies**

√ It uses a big range of .Net techniques from Console applications to Windows Applications and Web Applications and from windows services to web Services and from crystal reports to customized tools for use in reporting modules, depending upon the Customer needs and requirements.

### Responsibilities

- ✓ Maintenance, bug fixing and adding new modules.
- Via Travels and Tours (An automation system for Via Travels and Tours Company):

# Via Travel System in a Glance

An application that helps the customer to automate all of its business processes like maintaining income tax information, Insurance information, providing different packages to its customers and a lot of other reporting services.

### **Tools & Technologies**

- √ Built in ASP .NET 2005 providing a back end SqlServer 2005
- √ Reporting done via crystal reports.

# Responsibilities

- √ Maintenance, bug fixing and adding new modules.
- ➤ **Elijah** a project for Automation of UncleJoe's ( <a href="www.UncleJoes.com">www.UncleJoes.com</a> ) business Our Client UncleJoe's is a featured Merchant on Amazon.Com and has an average feedback rating of above 98%.

### Elijah in a Glance

- √ A Catalog Management System (Currently in development and production).
- ➤ Elijah covers all the business flow of catalog management and the Integration of the system with multiple e-business portals like Amazon, eBay, Froogle etc. Using XML and Web services.
- > Elijah Automates all the business flow of UncleJoe's, It automatically gets the XML catalog as well as inventory of TrueValue ( <a href="www.TruValue.Com">www.TruValue.Com</a>) via FTP, applies Staging, rectification of items, Calculates price and all Business rules defined by client. The application performs mapping of items from TrueValue hierarchy to Amazon (<a href="www.Amazon.Com">www.Amazon.Com</a>) hierarchy and provides end user an interface that will allow upload and download of items and their different reports covering a vast area of applications.
- > Application is designed to work with Amazon.com, eBay.com, Froogle.Com etc and is currently handling all online business logic on Amazon for the client.

#### **Tools & Technologies**

- > The application also utilizes a vast collection of technologies from .NET web services to console applications and from SqlServer Jobs to Data Transformation Services and from generating simple reports to automatically notifying customers of their Order's arrival and their dispatch to provide full automation of business process.
- > Application provides a web interface to users to fully control the Business flow.
- > Application utilizes Amazon Web Services to almost the maximum of its features offered via SOAP and XML.

#### Responsibilities

➤ I was responsible for development/ maintaining of different modules of this project. In addition to programming, I was also responsible for requirement analysis, task estimation, bug fixing/ maintenance.